ILGWU Publication "The Ladies' Garment Worker" 5780/070
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Publication "The Ladies' Garment Worker"
1911-1918
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/070
2.5 cubic feet
2.5 linear ft.
Publications (documents).
The collection contains both bound and unbound volumes of The Ladies' Garment Worker.
6322964
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 14, 2008
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 11, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
First published by the ILGWU in April 1910, the Ladies' Garment Worker was the official organ of the International and issued monthly in Yiddish, English, and Italian. In 1919, the Ladies' Garment Worker ceased publication and Justice became the official organ of the ILGWU.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of issues of the Ladies' Garment Worker published between 1911 and 1917. Issues from the publication's first year (1910) and its final year (1918) are available on microfilm.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/070 mf: ILGWU Publication "The Ladies' Garment Worker" on Microfilm 5780/051 PUBS: ILGWU Publications Justice 5780/051 mf: ILGWU Justice on Microfilm 5780/180: ILGWU Publication "Justice" Index 5780/185 mf: ILGWU Publication "Gerechtigkeit" (Justice) on Microfilm 5780/186: ILGWU Publication "Giustizia" (Justice) 5780/186 mf: ILGWU Publication "Giustizia" (Justice) on Microfilm 5780/201: ILGWU Publication "Justicia" (Justice)
Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Textile workers -- New York (State) -- New York; Textile workers -- United States
6322964
- Ladies' Garment Worker., 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  vol.2:no.6-12 (1911:June-Dec.)
- Ladies' Garment Worker., 1912 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  vol.3:no.1-12 (1912:Jan.-Dec.)
- Ladies' Garment Worker., 1913 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  vol.4:no.1-12 (1913:Jan.-Dec.)
- Ladies' Garment Worker., 1914 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  vol.5:no.1-12 (1914:Jan.-Dec.)
- Ladies' Garment Worker., 1915 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  vol.6:no.1-12 (1915:Jan.-Dec.)
- Ladies' Garment Worker., 1916 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  vol.7:no.1-12 (1916:Jan.-Dec.)
- Ladies' Garment Worker., 1917 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  vol.8:no.1-12 (1917:Jan.-Dec.)
- Ladies' Garment Worker, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  vol. 4: no. 1-12 (1913: Jan.-Dec.)
- Ladies' Garment Worker, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Ladies' Garment Worker, 1912-1916 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  vol. 3: no. 9 (1912: Sep.); vol. 7: no. 1-5 (1916: Jan.-May)
- Ladies' Garment Worker, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  vol. 7: no. 6-8; 11-12 (1916: Jun.-Aug., Nov.-Dec.)
- Ladies' Garment Worker, 1917 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  vol. 8: no. 1-4 (1917: Jan.-Apr.)
- Ladies' Garment Worker, 1917 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  vol. 8: no. 5-10 (1917: May-Oct.)
- Ladies' Garment Worker, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  vol. 9: no. 1-4 (1918: Jan.-Apr.)
- Ladies' Garment Worker, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  vol. 9: no. 5-6; 8-10 (1918: May-Jun., Aug.-Oct.)
- Ladies' Garment Worker, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  vol. 6: no. 1-12 (1915: Jan.-Dec.)
- Text digitized from the collection. (Box 6)